平铺阵列。
Flattening an array.
嗯，嗯。
Mm, yes.
我们可以用平的平面地图之类的
We could use flat, flat map or
something like that.
但因为这是一次面试
But because it's an interview,
我想知道你了解减少数据结构的方式有多好。
I wanna see how well you understand
reducing data structure.
您如何了解数组方法，了解一般数组的程度如何 ?
How well you understand array methods, how
well do you understand arrays in general?
艾拉我希望能有个加薪的
[LAUGH] Arrays, I wish I can get a raise.
如往常一样我们会以同样的方式开始
As usual, we'll start off the same way.
谢谢你我有时间笑了
Thank you, I got some laughs that time.
>> [LAUGH] >> 我们将以相同方式启动。
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; We'll start off the same way.
因此，我需要创建一个函数来平铺数组。
So, I need to create a function
to flatten an array.
所以，我需要一个功能，我们称它为扁平化，平平。
So, I need a function and
we'll call it flatten, flatter.
我们知道它需要一个阵列。
And we know it takes an array.
现在我们想做什么
Now, what do we wanna do?
我们在想什么
What are we thinking?
或者最终，我们知道我们要返回一个阵列。
Or eventually,
we know we wanna return an array.
所以我可以从这里开始
So I could start here.
我可以说回一个新阵列新阵列
I could say return someNewArray,
new array.
我们也许会改变这一切但这也会起作用
We're probably gonna change this but
this will work too.
有许多不同的方法来解决这个问题。
There are many different
ways to do this problem.
我要用我最喜欢的功能或者我最喜欢的方法
I'm gonna use my favorite function, or
my favorite method, which is reduce.
所以我会说 arr.l 减
So I'm gonna say arr.reduce.
而还原剂，那么，它们有四个参数。
And reducer, well,
they take four arguments.
但你真正关心的是蓄电池
But the ones you actually care
about are the accumulator,
我要说的是蓄电池和实际的物品
which I'm gonna say the accumulator,
and the actual item itself.
让我们把这个做完
And let's finish this out.
并且减少其他的争论，这就是你想开始的事情。
And reduce takes the other argument,
which is the thing you wanna start with.
这将成为累加人。
So this will be the accumulator.
这将是我们的基本值，它只是一个数组。
This will be our base value,
which is just an array.
好的冷静冷静
Okay, cool, cool.
所以我现在正在做的是我正在研究这个阵列。
So mentally what I'm doing is
now I'm looking at the array.
我在看数据结构。
I'm looking at the data structure.
这个项目将会是我开始的地方
The item is gonna be one because
this is where I started,
我只是在开始我的迭代
I'm just starting out my iteration.
所以我想看看指数为零的项目，在这个情况下是一个，但是
So I wanna check if the item at index
zero, which would be one in this case, but
就说我不知道我想看看是个数字还是
let's say I didn't know that,
I wanna check if it's a number or
如果是阵列的话
if it's an array.
执行此操作的方法是 Array.isArray。
And the way to do that is Array.isArray.
所以我可以说如果这个项目
So I can say, if the item,
实际上是说 Array.isArray
actually say Array.isArray,
检查它是否为项。
check if it's an item.
我马上就处理好了
I'll deal with that in a second.
它会变得更复杂
It gets a little more complicated.
但如果不是数组我想做什么
But if it's not an array,
what do I wanna do?
我想把它归还给我的累加人
I wanna just return it to my accumulator.
所以我会说 acc.push
So I'm gonna say acc.push.
我要把这个项目变成我想要的累加器
And I'm gonna push the item into
the accumulator that I wanna eventually
建立起来。
build up to.
最后这会让我每次都在做还原剂
And then, ultimately,
this will get me every time on reducers,
你得把累加器退回去
you have to return the accumulator.
缺省情况下，它不会返回。
It doesn't return by default.
所以，我们做了一个，我们有一个新的阵列，有两个，
So, we did one,
we have one in our new array, we have two,
我们的新阵列中有两个废物
we have two in our new array, crap.
现在我们点击一个阵列，一个不同的阵列。
Now we hit an array, a different array.
我们现在做什么
What do we do now?
我需要一个减少这个阵列的方法。
I need a way of reducing this array down.
所以我们要用所谓的 " 递归"
So we're gonna use what we call recursion,
递归是通过调用函数来减小值的概念。
recursion is the idea of reducing a value
down by calling the function over and
再一次又一次，这个价值就会变小一点。
over again and every time,
the value gets a little bit smaller.
你不用再用递归的方式
You don't have to use recursion for this,
有很多不同的方法来解决这个问题，但是
there are many different
ways to solve this, but
这一特殊问题本身就会产生递归。
this particular problem lands
itself well to recursion.
所以在某个时候我想做的就是
So at some point,
what I wanna do is I need to concatenates,
我得把这个减少了
I need to reduce this down.
一旦它平坦，我就可以将它连接到另一个阵列中。
Once it's flat,
I can concatenate that into another array.
所以我会说项目我会说
So I'll say item and I'm gonna say
我想在这里做什么
item., what do I wanna do here?
我想说的是
I wanna say concat.
从本质上来说，把这个项目缩小到实际上是没有的。
Essentially, concat this
item down into- actually no.
不我想做的就是要把它扁平
No, what I wanna do is
I wanna flatten this.
假设我的扁平化功能最终会起作用
Assuming my flatten function
will work eventually,
我想把这件物品放下
I wanna flatten this item down.
现在，该项已被序列化。
So the item is now flattened.
我想把这个分成另一个
I wanna concatenate this
down into the other thing.
这就是我一直把我弄扁的事你搞砸了
This is what always gets me on flatten
is you get messed up with types.
我现在有什么事了
I'm like, what do I have now?
我有个阵列吗我有个项目吗
Do I have an array, do I have an item?
Flatten 将返回一个阵列。
Flatten is gonna return an array.
那么我们对阵列做什么 ?
So what do we do with arrays?
我们把这些都连上了
We concatenate those.
所以，我可以说，其实我要缩短这个时间。
So, I can say, actually,
I'm gonna shorten this.
它会回来的
It's gonna return here.
省省吧
Save me some time.
然后我会说退让
And then I'm gonna say concacts.
事实上是的是的
Actually, yeah, yes.
这才是解决问题的办法
That's the solution.
大家都跟着吗
Does everybody follow?
有很多方法可以做到这一点，这是其中之一。
There are many ways to do this,
this is one of them.
所以我们有一个阵列。
So we have an array.
我们对数组进行迭代，直到我们命中数组，然后再进行并置
We iterate over the array until we
hit an array, then we concatenate by
以递归方式调用我们自己的函数，因为我们最终知道了，
recursively calling our own function,
because we know eventually,
这将返回或返回序列化的数组。
this will return in or
it'll return a flattened array.
所以不管我们的嵌套方式有多深
So it doesn't matter how
deeply nested we go here,
一旦完成返回，它将始终返回阵列。
it will always return an array
once it is done returning.
这就是递归的力量。
And that's the power of recursion.
一些问题让他们自我完善，有些问题则不存在。
Some problems lend themself
well to recursion, some do not.
但一般来说，这就像是你在更深更深地潜水的地方
But generally it's something like this
where you're diving deeper and deeper and
但最终你还是想放弃
deeper, but
eventually you wanna bubble back up.
递归是一个很好的解决方案。
Recursion is a good solution to it.
不错一点也不错
Not bad, not bad at all.
其实我忘了一件事
Actually, I forgot one thing.
我忘了累加器等于
I forgot to, Accumulator equals,
把那个切了我要换个小一点
cut that, and
I'm gonna change that a little bit.
就像我说的如果我在这里有点小问题
And like I said, if I'm syntactically
a little off here, that's okay,
这个想法是有效的
the idea stands.
如果你能得到那么多的解决方案，足够好，这就足够了
If you can get this far some solution,
good enough, this is good enough for
白板问题。
a whiteboard problem.
所以，别在推特上说，如果我在某个地方犯了一个小错误。
So, don't at me on Twitter,
if I've made a small mistake somewhere.
推特很恶毒太邪恶了
Twitter's vicious, it's vicious.